先生  你也太过分了
This is outrageous, sir.
别看你衣冠楚楚的  简直就是放高利贷
Y-you are nothing but a well-dressed loan shark.
罗杰斯女士  我向你保证
Ms. Rodgers, I assure you,
这个贷款利率已经很低了
this is a very competitive interest rate...
鉴于你以往的财政状况
...considering your financial history.
但如果你儿子为你连署...
However, if your son cosigns--
-可以  -不行不行
- Yes. - No, no, no, no.
这是我的贷款  不是他的
This is my loan, not his,
要维修的是我的表演工作室  不是他的
to pay for repairs to my acting studio, not his.
你就让我和你连署吧
If you just let me cosign the loan,
或者我可以直接把钱给你
or I could just give you the money.
理查德  我现在是女商人
Richard, I'm a businesswoman now.
我不想要你的钱  也不想要你签名
I do not want your money. I do not want your signature.
非常感谢
Thank you very much.
要守原则
It's the principle.
错了  罗杰斯女士
No, Ms. Rodgers,
要讲利率[兴趣]
It's the interest.
我已经没兴趣了  失陪
And I've just lost mine. Excuse me.
我现在投入了
I have $1 million...
一百万美金  所以...
into this now, so...
有什么事  卡塞尔
What do you want, Castle?
告诉我你需要我
Tell me you need me.
什么
Excuse me?
我被困在银行了
I'm stuck at a bank,
帮我妈申请贷款
helping my mother get a loan from my banker.
求求你告诉我有谋杀案
Please tell me that there's a murder somewhere
需要我们处理
we could be solving.
抱歉
Uh, sorry,
要尸体没有  文书工作倒有很多
there is no dead body, just a lot of paperwork,
欢迎前来分担  就这一次
which welcome you to come and do your share for once.
不知道困在这里
I wonder if it's worse being here or
和文书工作哪个更糟
being there doing paperwork.
为什么我们携手缉拿罪犯
You know how can we be partners when I'm chasing down bad guys,
一遇到文书工作  我就孤身一人了
and as soon as there are paperwork, I'm on an solo mission?
怎么
What?
我觉得这家银行马上就要被抢了
I think this bank is about to be robbed.
是吗  你就真这么无聊吗
Really? Are you that bored?
这里有一男一女
There's a man and a woman here
穿着手术服
dressed in scrubs,
而且上衣都可疑地鼓出来
and both of them have suspicious bulges in their jackets.
卡塞尔  我看是你的作家的想象力
Castle, I think your writer's imagination
又天马行空了吧
is getting away with you.
所有人  趴下
Everybody, get down on the floor!
这不是我的想象
It's not my imagination.
这绝对不是我的想象
It's definitely not my imagination.
快走  快到那边去
Move, move, move, move, move, move, move, move.
我的老天
Oh my god!
卡塞尔  出什么事了
Castle, what's happening?
天啊
Oh, my god.
都趴下  趴下  快点
On the floor! Get down! Move, move.
好的  好的
Ok, ok.
你在哪
Where are you?
莱克斯街的新阿姆斯特丹信托银行
I'm at the New Amsterdam Bank & Trust on Lex.
埃斯波西托  有抢劫案
Esposito, there's a 10-30,
在莱克斯街的新阿姆斯特丹信托银行
New Amsterdam Bank & Trust on Lex.
快派警队
Call dispatch.
我们什么时候开始处理银行抢劫案了
10-30? Since when we are handling bank-robbery cause?
卡塞尔在那里
Castle's there.
把手机都扔出来  快点
Slide up your cell phones. Now!
-手机  -都速度点
- Cell phones. - Hurry up, now, come on!
还不快点交出来  扔过来
Yo, you get that one? Slide that up here.
我说了  把你手机扔出来
I said slide up your mobiles!
-从柜台出来  -交出来  快点
- Move away from your stations. - Slide 'em up. Come on.
我和我妈妈躲在一张桌子后面
I'm hiding behind a desk with my mother,
但我能看清所有情况
but I can see everything.
他们穿着手术服
They're wearing doctor scrubs.
其中一个在从柜台里拿钱
One of them is emptying the cash drawers.
银行经理  你过来
You, bank manager... move over here.
另一个抓住了银行经理
Another one is going for the bank manager.
他拿了经理的钥匙
He's getting manager's key.
他往银行最里面走了
He's going to the back of bank.
已经派警车去了
We got squad cars en route.
卡塞尔  你仔细听好
Castle, I need you to listen very carefully.
他们有几个人
How many are there?
三个
There are three.
四个
Make that four.
看来要用你杀鸡儆猴了
So you're the hero I'm gonna make an example of.
抱歉  你的朋友现在没空
Sorry. Your friend can't talk right now.
我要是你就不担心他  而担心自己
I wouldn't worry about him. I'd worry about yourself.
已经有警车在路上了
I've got squad cars on their way.
你是警察
Are you a cop?
你报警了
You called a cop?
没有  你们进来的时候我们已经在通话了
No. We were already on line when you guys came in.
听我说  现在还没有人受伤
Listen to me. So far, nobody has been hurt
也没有财产被盗
and nothing has been stolen.
所以现在如果你们就如来时一般离去
So if you just leave the same way that you came in,
就可以消失得无影无踪
you can just disappear.
你是要承诺不会来找我们吗
You gonna promise not to come look for me?
我不找  我追杀
I don't look. I hunt.
相信我  你可不想要那种结果
And trust me, you don't want that.
所以现在离开
So leave now,
这就只不过是在小版块登出的
and this will just be a quirky little article
一篇奇谈而已
in the metro section.
抱歉  亲爱的
Sorry, sweetheart.
我更想上头版
I'd rather make the front page.
我们走
Let's go.
豪瑟尔医生  奎恩医生
Dr. Howser, Dr. Quinn,
警察会比我们预期的早到
Cops are gonna be here sooner than we thought.
趴下  和其他人一样
Now kiss the floor, like the others.
快点  你也是  趴下
Come on. You, too. Get down.
赫斯特布尔医生  我们走
Dr. Huxtable, let's go.
摄像头已经摧毁
Bank cameras are down.
存储驱动盘也销毁了
Memory drives are destroyed.
警察
Cops!
好了  医生们  我们受过训练
All right, doctors, we trained for this.
你们知道该怎么做
You know what to do.
看来我们要好好了解彼此一番了
Looks like we're all gonna get to know each other a lot better.
我要特警队分析  情况报告
I want SWAT analysis, sitrep,
银行蓝图  五分钟到我手上
building blueprints, five minutes.
你是谁
Who are you?
凯特·贝克特探长  凶杀调查组的
Detective Kate Beckett, homicide.
若有伤亡我会通知的
I'll be sure to call if someone dies.
现在请你在外面等候
Meanwhile, I need you to step outside...
不是  长官  我的搭档在银行里
No, sir. My partner is in that bank.
等等  里面有警察吗
Wait. We got a cop in there?
他是个平民调查员
He's a civilian investigator.
他们抢劫银行时我和他正好在通话
He and I were on the phone when they took over the bank.
他说里面有四名嫌犯
He said that there's four suspects in there.
均身着手术服
They're dressed up in doctor scrubs.
还有什么信息
Anything else you can tell me?
我和其中一名嫌犯通过话
Yeah, I spoke with one of the suspects.
他的表现如何
Then what was his demeanor?
冷静  事实上  非常冷静
Calm, actually. Very calm.
感谢提供信息
Thanks for the intel.
我们会尽一切可能把你的搭档平安救出来
We'll do everything we can to get your partner out safe.
我们下一步怎么做
Okay, so what's our next move?
你要做的是离开我的指挥站
Well, your next move is to leave my command post.
你想帮你搭档
You want to help your partner,
就让我做好我的工作
let me do my job.
和银行接通电话
I need a line to that bank.
我要和这家伙谈谈
I want to talk to this guy.
遵命  长官
Yes, sir.
你该走了  探长
You miss your cue, detective.
好了
All right.
我把话说清楚
I'm gonna make this real simple.
只要你动
You move...
你就得死
You die.
懂了吗
Got it?
有人受伤吗
Is anyone hurt?
那就好
All right.
放轻松
Stay relaxed.
按他们说的去做
Do as they say.
我们会平安度过的
We'll get through this.
警察会救我们出去的
The cops will get us out.
有什么发现吗
What did you find out?
他们不需要我们的帮助
That our services aren't needed.
埃斯波西托  你在紧急应变小组还有熟人吗
Espo, do you still have buddies in E.S.U.?
有
Of course.
好  我要知道他们掌握了什么情况
Good. I want to know what they know.
然后去搜查重案资料
And let's get ahold of major crimes,
看看有没有其他手法类似的抢劫案
find out if there are any other rubberies with similar M.O.s.
我们对劫匪了解得越多
The more we know about these guys,
就越占优势
the more leverage we got.
贝克特探长
Detective Beckett.
彼得森队长有话对你说
Captain Peterson would like a word.
你说说  你是怎么想的
Tell me, what were you thinking?
我只是想帮忙  长官
I was just trying to help out, sir.
怎么帮  诱惑银行劫匪吗
What, by charming the bank robber?
-什么  -我们和他通上话了
- What? - We get him on the horn,
可我一句话都还没套出来
but before I can get two words out,
他就说  他只和那位
he says, and I quote, "I will only talk
声音性感的女警官说话
to the lady cop the one with the bedroom voice."
你想插手吗
Yeah. You wanted in?
那你就来吧
Well, you're in.
不  长官
No, sir.
我没受过任何人质谈判方面的训练
I don't have any training in hostage negotiations.
我没时间给你上培训课了
Well, I don't have time to give you a seminar,
你就这么记着
so think of it like this--
凡是凶案组训练教你做的
you do the opposite of what ever
都别做  懂了吗
homicide training tells you, okay?
所以不要大喊大叫  不要逼迫对方
So don't yell, don't bully,
别用任何方式威胁他
don't--don't threaten him in any way.
总之要稳住他们
It's all about keeping them calm.
探长
Detective...
你准备好了吗
You up for this?
是的  没问题
Yeah. Yeah, absolutely.
现在最重要的是让他保持通话
Now it's important to keep him talking.
你需要起建立良好的关系
You gotta build a rapport.
只要他忙着说话  就不会去伤害人质
As long as he's busy talking, he's not busy hurting hostages.
-懂了  -懂了吗
- Okay. - Okay?
谁啊
Who's this?
我是贝克特探长
This is Detective Kate Beckett.
我听说你想和我通话
I understand that you wanted to speak with me.
没错  我不喜欢刚才那个警察
Yeah, I don't like that other guy.
我也不喜欢他
Yeah, me neither.
你要我建立起良好关系的
You said to build a rapport.
你叫什么名字
So what's your name?
你可以叫我捕手约翰
You can call me Trapper John.
《陆军野战医院》的粉丝吗  不错
A "MASH" fan? It's nice.
你那边情况怎么样啊
So how you doin'?
有什么能帮你做的吗
Anything I can do to help?
凯特啊  凯特
Oh, Kate, Kate, Kate,
你在按着那傻瓜的方案进行  是吧
You're running that idiot's playbook, aren't you?
那位自信满满的队长对你说了什么
What did Captain Confidence tell you,
安抚我的情绪
keep me calm,
建立良好关系
build a rapport,
获取有效信息
extract information.
规矩是这样的
Here's how it's gonna work--
你骗我  我杀人质
You lie to me, I kill hostages.
你耍我  我杀人质
You jerk me around, I kill hostages.
你们强攻  我也杀人质
If you storm the bank, I kill hostages.
还有  凯特
And, Kate...
我会先拿你男朋友开刀
I'll start with your boyfriend.
我们知道了一件事
Well, we learned one thing.
什么事
What's that?
他不是什么一觉醒来
He's not a punk who just woke up
突然兴起要抢银行的小流氓
and decided to rob a bank.
他心里很有数  还知道我们的方案
He knows what he's doing. He knows our playbook.
这家伙是职业劫匪
This guy's a pro.
特警队切入银行监控摄像头了吗
S.W.A.T tap into the, uh, camera the bank yet?
还在进行中  长官
Stil working on it, sir.
四号线上有位银行总行的苏珊·克雷格找
Also there's a Susan Craig from the bank's main branch on line 4.
长官  你要我做些什么
Sir, what do you want me to do?
-什么都不用做  -什么
- Nothing. - I'm sorry?
这不是凶杀案  探长
It's not a homicide, detective.
不需要向前推进
Not about moving forward
或是挖掘下一个线索
or digging for the next clue.
我们这里有时按兵不动  才是最佳策略
Here somthimes, no move is the best move.
让捕手约翰考虑一下
Let Trapper John think about things
我们再打电话
and we'll call him back.
你知道吗  这都是你的错
This is your fault, you know?
他报了警
He called the cops.
我看见了
I saw him.
要不是这个人
If it wasn't for this guy,
劫匪们抢了钱就走了
the bank robbers would've come and gone,
我们就能离开了
we'd all be outta here.
不是这样的  警察迟早会来的
No. No, the cops were coming anyway.
那帮劫匪  是他们搞砸了
The bank robbers, they screwed up.
他们取出了现金抽屉最下面的钞票
They pulled the bottom bills from the cash drawer.
那会自动拉响无声警报的  知道吗
Which automatically triggers the silence alarm, ok?
这不是任何人的错
No one's fault.
西蒙娜
Simone,
你怀孕几个月了
how far along are you?
八个月了
32 weeks.
竟然让孕妇作人质
Holding a pregnant woman hostage?
他们应该放了你
They should let you go.
女士  他们不会放人走的
Lady, they're not letting her go.
不会让任何一个人走的
They're not letting any of us go.
我看过这种电影  我知道下场会如何
I've seen this movie before. I know how it ends.
我们都得死
All of us dead.
我们不会死的
We are not gonna die.
我们会没事的
We gonna be fine.
我和警察一起工作  我的搭档会救我们出去的
I work with the police, and my partner's gonna get us out.
赫斯特布尔医生
Dr. Huxtable.
达文波特先生
Mr. Davenport,
后面那些门通向哪里
what's behind those doors back there?
厕所  休息室  保安室
Restroom, break rooms, security room,
还有保管箱室
and the safety deposit boxes.
我看到他们从你脖子上夺走了一把钥匙
I saw them take a key from around your neck.
那把是开什么的
What does it open?
那是我开保管箱室的保安钥匙
Yeah, that's my security key for the safety deposit boxes.
有蹊跷
Somethg is going on here.
这边有满满一金库的现金
Why does he keep going back there
他却不拿  反而一直往后面走
when there's a vault full of cash up there untouched.
理查德  我见过这表情
Richard, I know that look.
求你了  好奇害死猫
Please, curiosity kill the cat.
这里面有什么隐情
Something weird is going on here.
我们得查明是什么事
We need to figure it out what it is.
而且我完全知道该怎么做
And I know exactly what to do.
妈妈  别担心
Don't worry, mother
在《虎胆龙威》里这招很管用的
I saw this work on "Die Hard".
这话真让人安心
Oh, great.
豪瑟尔先生
Uh, Mr. Howser.
不好意思  该叫豪瑟尔医生
Excuse me, Dr. Howser.
你想死是吧
You got a death wish?
不  我只是尿急
No, just a small bladder.
不幸的是
And, uh, unfortunately,
看起来我们还得在这里呆上一阵子
it looks like we're gonna be here for a while.
所以  除非你希望这里一片狼藉
So unless you like it messy,
现在最好
now might be a good time
安排大家轮流上厕所
to start arranging some restroom runs.
谢了
Thank you.
为什么选天才小医生的名字呢
So... why Doogie Howser?
明明有那么多响亮的电视医生名可选
I mean, there's so many cool TV doctors you could pick--
豪斯医生  谢博德医生  菲尔医生
Dr. House, Dr. Shepherd, Dr. Phil.
闭嘴
Shut up.
有什么消息吗
Anything?
全是坏消息
All bad news.
紧急应变小组无法得到里面的情况
E.S.U. can't get eyes or ears inside.
银行的监控摄像头已被破坏
Bank cameras are disable,
墙也太厚了  没办法从外面钻进去
the walls are too thick to drill from outside.
那如果紧急应变小组强攻进银行呢
So what if E.S.U. storms the bank?
那将是毫无准备之仗
That'll be going in blind.
以你的经验来看  这种情况下
And in your experience, in this scenario
人质生还的可能性有多大
what are the hostages' chance of survival?
之前的事我很抱歉
Hey, um, I'm sorry about before--
没事的
Oh, please.
-这...  -那是工作职责所在
- It's-- - It's the job.
-是啊  -其实我是你的影迷
- Yeah. - Actually, I'm a fan.
《仲夏夜之梦》
"A Midsummer Night's Dream,"
-你扮演蒂坦妮娅  -我的天啊
- you played Titania... - Oh, my Goodness.
在公园里演莎士比亚的戏剧
In Shakespeare in the park.
那都是80年代的事了
That was in the '80s.
你怎么还能记得呢
How could you possibly remember that?
你太令人难忘了
Oh, you're unforgettable.
如果非死不可
If I have to die,
我很高兴能跟看过我作品的人一起死
I'm glad I'm going with someone who knows my work.
谢谢你
Thank you.
好了  还有谁要去厕所
All right. Who else needs the loo?
我去
I'll go.
有什么发现吗
Did you learn anything?
两件事
Two things.
第一  这家银行的洗手间挺不错的
Firstly, the restrooms here at the bank are quite lovely,
只是没有窗户
excepting for the lack of windows
或者其他能逃跑的出口
or any other means of escape.
第二  也更重要的是
Second, and more importantly,
我说对了
I was right.
确实有点不对劲
Something odd is going on.
我刚才看见捕手约翰在保管箱室里面
I saw Trapper John in the safe deposit box room,
他抽出一个箱子
he pulled out a box
把里面的信件和照片拿走了
and he was removing letters and photos.
而且他不是撬开的  他用的两把钥匙
And he didn't break in, either. He used both keys.
一把是我的经理钥匙
Well, one's my manager's key.
另一把一定是保管箱主人的钥匙
The other one must be owner's key.
捕手约翰选这个时候从自己的
Is this a very strange time for Trapper John
保管箱里拿东西  真是奇怪啊
to get something from his safe deposit box.
我认为这个箱子不是他的
Well, I'm assuming the box isn't his.
这些人是有意触发警报的
These guys set off the alarm on purpose.
他们想要造成人质危机
They wanted this hostage stand up.
我是说  看看这些家伙
I mean, come on. Look at these guys.
他们是职业劫匪  对吗
They're professionals, right?
他们该知道不能取走
They know better than to take
现金抽屉最下面的钞票
the bottom bills from the cash draw.
为什么呢
But why?
时间
Time.
保管箱钥匙上面没有号码
Safe deposit box keys don't have numbers on them.
如果这不是他自己的钥匙
So if it's not his key,
他在找到正确的箱子前要挨个试
he'd have to try every lock until he got to the right box,
那样会很费时间
and that would take time.
好了  达文波特先生
Okay, Mr. Davenport,
他抽出来的那个箱子
the--the box he pulled
是在北面的墙上
was on the north wall.
从左往右第四栏  从上往下第三个
It was four columns over, three boxes down.
那应该是
That would be box...
120号箱子
120.
好的
Okay.
知道箱子的主人是谁
We figure out whose box that is,
就知道这些人的真正目的了
we can figure out what these people are really up to.
没错  但我不认为
Yeah, well, I don't think
他们会让我们用电脑
they're gonna let us use the computer.
也许不用电脑也行
Maybe we won't have to.
妈妈  你过生日我送你的手镯呢
Mother, the bracelet I gave you for your birthday.
不行  我好喜欢这个手镯
Oh, no. I love this bracelet.
好吧
All right.
队长  是他
Captain, it's him.
牢记策略
Remember the strategy.
知道
Yeah.
你那边怎么样了
Hey. How's it going?
目前还好
So far, so good.
好  那人质们呢
Yeah, and how are the hostages?
我很想知道怀了孕的银行出纳西蒙娜怎么样了
Pretty concerned about the pregnant Bank Teller Simone.
现在这个状况很紧张
It's kind of a stressful situation.
你还是放她出来吧
You might wanna get her out of there.
不不不  凯特
No, no, no, Kate.
将欲取之  必先予之
You gotta give before you can receive.
好吧  你有什么条件
Okay. What would you like?
一辆大巴
A bus...
车窗着色
with tinted windows,
载着我和同伴们
that'll take me, my partners,
还有人质们去提特波罗机场
and my hostages to Teter Boro Airport.
在那  你要预备一架飞机
There, you're gonna have a plane waiting
载我们去我指定的国家  你做到了这些
to take to the foreign country of my choosing, now you do that,
我就放了怀孕的出纳员
I give you the knocked up Bank Teller.
等我们可以逍遥快活了
Once we land in paradise,
我就放了其余人质
I'll release the rest hostages.
凯特
And, Kate...
给你三小时准备
you got three hours.
好吧  孟菲斯  给我找一辆
All right, Monfriez, find me a bus
车窗着色的大巴来
with tinted windows and get it over here.
等等  你真要答应他这些条件吗
Wait a minute. You're actually giving him what he wants?
当然不是  那家伙想从那儿出来
Of course not. The only way that guy is leaving the building
要么是被逮住  要么是死掉
is either in handcuffs or a body bag.
但到时候
But if it comes to it,
可以利用大巴引蛇出洞
I can use that bus to lure the robbers out
再让狙击手收拾他们
and have snipers take 'em out.
怎么...
What the...
看见了吗
You see that?
是的
Yeah.
那是摩斯密码
That's morse code.
理查德  停下
Stop, Richard.
危险解除
Clear.
S-D-B-1-2-0
Uh, s-d-b-1-2-0,
一遍又一遍  你觉得是什么意思
Over and over again. What do you think it means?
某人的姓名首字母或者代码之类的
Someone's initials or a code.
-当天银行  -保留小数
- Same day bank. - Save decimal--
等等  等等  保...
Wait. Wait, sa--
可能是  保险  保险
Um, could be, uh... safe. Safe?
S-D-B  保管箱
S-d-b. Safe deposit box.
120号保管箱  就是这个了
Safe deposit box 120. That's it.
真的吗  保管箱
Really? What would a safe deposit box
跟这事能有什么关系
have to do with anything?
不清楚  但是卡塞尔以身犯险
I don't know, but if Castle when to the trouble
发了这个信息  就肯定有用
of sending that message, it means something.
你怎么知道是他发的
How do you know it's him?
相信我  肯定是他
Trust me, it's him.
120号保管箱属于一对夫妇
Safe deposit box number 120 belongs to a married couple
安格斯和吉迪恩·菲尔斯
Agnes&Gideon Fields.
这个箱子有什么特别吗
Anything special about the box?
没有  只有银行记录显示他们每月来查看一次
No, just that bank record show they both access it monthly.
我让我手下去查查
I'll get my team to check it out.
理查德
Richard...
快装纯  快装纯
Be innocent, be innocent.
你太明显了
You're indicating.
你瞧  外行也分得出演技差的人
See? Even a layman can spot an uninspired performance.
是的  妈妈
Yes, Mother.
我回来的时候
When I was coming back,
往他们的帆布袋里瞟了一眼
I-I got a glimpse inside their--their duffle bag.
看见了一些带金属丝
There were white bricks
和计时器的白色砖状物体
with wires and timers attached to it.
我猜那可能是C-4炸药
I-I think it could be C-4.
C-4炸药  你确定吗
C-4? Are you sure?
是的  他们会把我们炸成碎片的
Yeah. They're gonna blow us all up.
-冷静  你得...  -让我怎么冷静啊
- Calm down. Just calm... - How could I supposed to calm down?
我还有个家要照顾呢
I’ve got a family to think about.
我们都有家
We all have families.
给姐冷静下来
Now, calm down.
你叫什么名字
What's your name?
-萨尔  萨尔·马丁诺  -好
- Sal. Sal Martino. - Okay.
萨尔  你有老婆  有孩子吧
You got a wife, Sal, kids?
对  我有个儿子
Yeah. I have a son.
他叫什么名字
What's his name?
康纳
Connor.
我敢说你现在满脑子都是
I bet the only thing you can think about
想再见到他  对吗
is seeing him again. Am I right?
你不知道我有多想
You have no idea.
很好
Good.
你现在只管想着这一件事
So you just keep thinking on that.
想着你很快就能再见到康纳
You think about how you gonna see Connor again real soon.
因为我会想办法帮大家离开这里
Because I'm gonna figur out ways to get all of us out of here.
我保证
I promise.
我有点喘不过气
I need some air.
可恶  这地方怎么没有新鲜空气
Damn. Why is there no air in this place?
这里到底是怎么回事
What the hell is going on here?
我原以为他们只是为了保管箱
I thought this was about a safe deposit box.
但他们为什么要用到炸药
Why would they need C-4?
可能他们不想让任何人知道他们偷了什么
Maybe they don't want anyone to know what they stole from that box
而把我们和银行都炸掉可以确保这一点
and the C-4 is to make sure that no one ever does.
安格斯和吉迪恩·菲尔斯  请开门
Agnes and Gideon Fields, open up, please.
纽约警局
This is NYPD.
这根本说不通
This doesn't make any sense.
一对老夫妻的银行保管箱
What could the old couple's safety deposit box
怎么会与这次银行劫案扯上关系
have to do what's going on in that bank?
可能有很大关系
Maybe everything.
银行方面说安格斯和吉迪恩
The bank said that Agnes and Gideon
每个月去查看一次他们的保管箱  对吗
were accessing their box once a month, right?
我刚刚收到分局发来的短信
I just got a text from the precinct.
吉迪恩·菲尔斯四年前就死了
Gideon Fields died four years ago.
所以去查看保管箱的人绝不是他
So whoever's accessing that box wasn't him.
安格斯  纽约警局
Agnes, this is NYPD.
请快开门
Open up, please.
广播开着
The radio's on.
我们不能就这么进去
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa. We can't go there.
我们没有搜查令  也没有正当依据
We--we don'hava waant.We don't have probable cause.
兄弟  现在事关卡塞尔的性命
Bro, Castle's life depends on this.
你听到了没
Did you just hear that?
我想我刚才听到了呼救声
I think I just heard someone yell out "Help, police!"
"救命啊"  又喊了一遍
"Help, police!" There it is again.
纽约警局  安格斯
NYPD! Agnes!
是啊
Yeah.
她是安格斯
It's Agnes.
到底怎么回事
What the hell is going on?
看来保管箱的主人
Looks like the owner of our safety deposit box
已经死了一个礼拜左右
has been dead maybe a week.
脖子上的痕迹显示她是被勒死的
Ligature marks on her neck indicate strangulation.
你们在案发现场发现了什么
What'd you find at the crime scene?
这地方被翻过
The place is trashed.
凶手像是在寻找什么东西
The killer was looking for something.
死者脖子上有一条坏了的钥匙链
There's a broken key chain necklace on the body,
但是钥匙已经不见了
But there's no key.
那大概就是她放银行保管箱钥匙的地方
OK, that might be where she kept the key for the safe deposit box.
我不明白
I don't get it
她是离休图书管理员
This is a little old retired librarian.
她的银行保管箱里能放什么东西
What could possibly be in her safe deposit box
值得别人做出这种事情
that would be worth doing all this.
纳粹时期的金币  核聚变材料
Nazi gold, cold fusion,
通往亚特兰蒂斯的地图
map to Atlantis.
嘿  小卡塞尔
Hey, Castle Jr.,
你能不能按正常警察的思路考虑这个问题
could you maybe start thinking like a cop, please?
我正是啊
I am.
是么
Are you?
这肯定是为了很重要的事
It had to have been something huge,
凶手才会杀她  不是吗
that was worth killing her over, right?
嘿  超级警察
Hey, super cop,
来看看这个
check it out.
-找到什么了  -窃听器
- What is it? - It's a bug.
不是从普通监视商店能买到的
It's not from a spy shop, either.
这看起来相当专业
This looks professional.
听着  我需要你们去挖掘
Listen, I need you to dig up
有关安格斯·菲尔斯的所有线索  我得挂了
everything you can on Agnes Fields. I gotta go.
他们在里面  是吗
They're here, aren't they?
我爸爸跟我奶奶
My dad and my gramma...
-我知道他们要来这儿  -阿丽克西斯
- I know they were coming to this bank... - Alexis
现在他们俩都不接电话
And no one's answering their phones,
我爸从来不会不接我电话
and my dad always takes my phone.
-而你也在  -听我说  他们会没事的
- And you're here. - Listen, everything is gonna be fine, OK?
他们确实是在里面
But they are inside that bank.
又怎么了
What is it?
我要到窗户那边
I need to get over to those windows
去通知贝克特这里有炸药
to get a message to Beckett about the c-4.
算了吧  理查德
Oh, come on, Richard.
求你了  那太危险了
Please. It is too dangerous.
我们是人质  拜托你安安心心当人质
We are hostages. Behave accordingly.
求你了
Please.
别去   理查德
Don't, Richard...
奎恩医生
Uh, dr. Quinn.
你又想怎么样
What's your problem?
奎恩医生  我接受的家教是
Uh, it's just, where I come from, Dr. Quinn,
我们不让孕妇坐在冰凉的地板上
we don't make pregnant women sit on hard floors.
我可否到沙发那儿拿几个垫子给她
Is it all right if I get some cushions from the sofa for her?
那就快点  帅小伙
Make it fast, pretty boy.
多谢
Thanks.
不要动
Stop!
说你呢
Oh! Right there!
不要动  否则我就要开枪了
Stop or I'm going to shoot.
空气  空气
Air. Air.
-我说了不要动  -我需要新鲜空气
- Hey! I said stop! - I need air.
不要开枪  不要开枪
Don't shoot! Don't shoot! I need...
别开枪  别开枪
Don't shoot! Don't shoot! Air.
萨尔  别这样
Sal, stop.
全都趴在地上
On the floor.
不要开枪
Don't! Don't shoot!
放轻松  别开枪
Easy! Easy! Don't shoot!
别开枪  别开枪
Don't shoot! Don't shoot.
他的癫痫发作了
He's having a seizure.
萨尔  放轻松 放轻松
Sal, easy, easy.
这下好了  癫痫症
Great, Epilepsy.
他需要帮助
This guy needs help.
那你赶紧帮他啊
Then help him.
奎恩医生  你瞧
Hey, look, Dr. Quinn,
他刚刚癫痫病发作
The man just had a grand mal seizure.
除非你是真的医生
So unless you realy are a medicine woman
他现在就得去医院
he needs a hospital now.
叫捕手约翰来  快点
Get Trapper John. Move!
太好了
Perfect.
一名冒牌医生叫来另一名冒牌医生来会诊
The fake doctor calls in another fake doctor for a consult.
我现在该怎么做
What am I supposed to do?
什么都不用做  我们正在竭尽全力
Nothing. We're doing everything we can.
你不会懂的  他们是我唯一的亲人
You don't understand. They're all I've got.
你懂吗  他们就是我的全部
Do you here me? They're all I've got.
阿丽克西斯  听我说  我向你保证
Alexis, listen to me, I promise you,
他们会没事的
they are gonna be okay.
最好是这样
They better.
来电话了
Incoming call.
我现在得走了  你陪着她
OK, I'm gonna go. Stay with her.
嗨  我是阿什  一会儿回你电话
Hey, it's Ash. I'll hit you back.
阿什我知道你忙  可我现在很需要你
Ash, I know you're busy, but I need you.
我爸爸  他
My dad, he's...
你得尽快回我电话
You've got to call me back right away,
越快越好
as soon as you get this.
我现在真的很需要你
I really need you.
听着凯特  刚才有个人质癫痫发作晕过去了
Look, Kate, one of the hostages just had a epileptic fit and passed out,
一般情况下  我根本不在乎
and normally, I wouldn't care,
但现在惹得其他人质心神不宁
but it's starting to upset the other hostages,
我不想他们里面有人逞英雄
and I don't want anyone trying to be a hero.
所以你听好了
So, here's the deal.
你们派一名急救医生进来
You're gonna send in one paramedic to getting in
而作为对我的慷慨的回报
in exchange for this generosity.
你们要在二十分钟内准备好我要的巴士
You're gonna have my bus right outside in 20.
时间不够
That's not enough time.
但对我来说足够了
But it is for me.
把这个男人带出去
Take this guy now,
然后在二十分钟内准备好我要的巴士
and get my bus outside in 20.
否则我就开始射杀人质了
Or I'll start popping hostages.
我们还要多久才能准备好他要的巴士
How soon till we get that bus?
三十五分钟
35 minutes.
你得向他要求更多的时间
You're gonna have to ask for more time.
他不会答应的
He's not gonna go for it.
那我们就要突袭银行了
Then we're gonna storm the bank.
我们不能冲进去
We can't storm the bank.
我们不知道匪徒和人质的具体位置
We don't know where anybody is in there.
如果我们冲进去  人质会没命的
If we go in there, hostages are just gonna get killed.
听好  如果我们想要救出他们
Listen, if we're gonna save any of them,
这是唯一的选择
we have no other choice.
也许有其他选择
Maybe we do.
我们可以利用生病的人质
We could use this sick hostage to our advantage.
不派救护人员进去
Instead of sending in a paramedic,
我们派一个受过战术训练的警察去
we send in a cop with tactical training.
这个警察可以获取
The cop gets intel
特警队突入时所需要的情报
for when S.W.A.T. goes in to breach the bank.
我想你有人选了
I'm guessing you have a cop in mind.
搜身
Search her.
安全
She's clear.
速度快点
Make it quick.
他怎么样
How's he doing?
不太好
Not good.
他叫萨尔·马丁诺
His name's Sal Martino.
他有癫痫症
He has epilepsy.
我估计因焦虑而病发
I think the seizure was prone by stress.
萨尔  嗨
Hey, Sal. Hey, buddy.
感觉怎么样
How you doing?
萨尔  听我说  你要知道
Sal, listen to me, I want you to know
外面有很在乎你的人
that there are people out there care about you,
保持呼吸
so just keep breathing.
我保证
I promise you
我会带你离开这里
I'll get you outta here.
别废话  快动手
Don't talk about it. Be about it.
还有你
And you...
帮忙把他抬上轮床  马上
Help get him on that gurney. Now!
萨尔  准备好了吗
Sal, you ready?
数到三我们就把你抬上轮床
We're gonna get you up on the count of three.
一  二  三
One, two, three.
就好  伙计
Okay, buddy.
放松伙计  好了
Easy buddy. Okay.
你没事的
You're all right.
行了
Okay.
你爸没事  他们俩都...很好
Your dad's okay. They're both... okay.
怎么了
What's wrong?
阿丽克西斯  我要你立刻退到黄线以后
Alexis, I need you to go behind that yellow line now.
-好的  -把她带到黄线之后去
- You got it. - Take her behind line.
-喂  -阿什利  我爸爸
- Hey. -Hey, Ashley, my father...
-等下  什么  -你能听见吗
- Wait, what? - Can you hear me?
晚点我再打给你
I'll call you later.
不  你不能晚点打给我
No, you can't call me later.
我当然可以
Of course I can.
阿什利  我听不清  什么  阿什利  我听不
Ashley, I can't hear. What? Ashley I can't...
-银行里有C4炸弹  -我没看到
- There's C-4 in the bank? - I didn't see any,
但是如果卡塞尔说有那就肯定有
but if Castle says it's in there it's in there.
那意味着武力突破是不可能了
Well, that means the breach is out of the question.
我不会让我的人冒着被炸的危险行动的
I'm not gonna send my boys into a bomb fight.
我们得在巴士上解决这些家伙
We're gonna have to take these guys out on the bus.
巴士还有20分钟才能到
That bus is still 20 minutes out.
他给的时限还有五分钟
His deadline is in five.
时间一到他就要开始杀人质了
He's gonna starting killing hostages.
我们得多争取点时间
Well, we have to buy more time.
我的巴士呢
Where's my bus?
巴士在路上  20分钟内到
The bus is on its way. It'll be there in 20 minutes.
2分钟后人质就要上西天了
The hostages will be dead in two.
别
No.
没人需要死
Nobody needs to die.
好吗  巴士正在路上  只是
Okay? It's coming. It's just--
-只是堵在路上了  -我们说好的  凯特
- It's stuck in traffic. - We have rules, Kate.
我承诺不杀人质
I said I won't kill anyone,
你承诺会给我巴士
you said you gave me a bus.
交易结束前我都遵守诺言
I live up to mine at the end of the deal.
我也会遵守我的承诺  只不过
And I'm gonna live up to mine, I just...
我警告过你别耍我
I warned you not to jerk me around.
后果我说得很清楚
Now I was clear about the consequences.
我是不是需要证明一下我是认真的
Do I need to approve how serious I am? Is that it?
我觉得我们该先做个深呼吸
Okay, I think we both just need to take a breath
然后再谈谈
and we can talk about--
我不谈了
I'm done talking!
怎么回事
What was that?
这一枪是警告  凯特
A warning shot, Kate.
下一枪就要死人了
The next one's for the kill.
-不许碰他  你这个混蛋  -达文波特  拖住她
- Don't you touch him, you son of a bitch! - Davenport, hold her back!
-把你手拿开  -我没事
- Keep your hands off! - I got this.
我会让你男友血流成河  凯特
I'm gonna make a pretty red stains at your boyfriend, Kate.
我正用枪对准他的喉咙
I got my gun to his throat
我要用他的内脏画一幅杰克逊·波洛克的画
and I'm gonna paint a Jackson Pollock with his insides.
你得让他冷静下来
You need to calm him down--
听我说  混蛋
Listen to me, jackass.
我控制不了交通
I do not control traffic,
所以你必须给我20分钟
so you're gonna have to give me 20 minutes.
-凯特  还剩一分钟  -不行
- Now you got one minute, Kate. - No.
20分钟
I've got 20.
听见没
Do you hear me?
20.
因为一旦你开了枪
Because if you pull that trigger,
我会走进去  亲手
I will walk through those doors and personally
用子弹打穿你的头
put a bullet through your skull.
好吧  凯特
Okay, Kate.
再给你20分钟
You got 20 more minutes.
还真是高端的谈判技巧啊
Well, that's one way to negotiate.
你的女朋友真带劲儿啊
Your girlfriend is a hellcat.
是啊  不过她不是我女朋友
Yeah, well, she's not my girlfriend.
她对你来说太彪悍了吗
She too much woman for you?
那你们为什么要抢这家银行呢
So why are you guys robbing this bank?
萨顿原则
Sutton's law.
当被问及为何抢银行时  威利·萨顿回答道
When asked why he robbed banks, Willie Sutton famously replied,
"银行有钱"
"Because that's where the money is."
只不过威利·萨顿从来没这么说过
Except Willie Sutton never said that.
只不过是个记者编造了这么一句话
It was a reporter who made up that quote.
你知道  我们作家就是这么厉害
You see, writers-- we're really good.
将事实变得神乎其神
Alternate reality to the fake narrative.
在我看来  你们现在的所作所为
And the story I see you guys spinning here
并不是为了钱
is really not about stealing money.
是吗
Is that so?
你和你同伙都不戴手套
You and your crew don't wear gloves.
明显你们不担心指纹被查
Obviously you're not worried about fingerprints,
也就是说你们没有前科
which means you're not in the system.
至于口音呢
And those accents?
你们是雇佣兵
You're mercs,
所以说你们只想尽快上车
which means you're just want to get on that bus.
那么  那盒子里是什么
So... what was in that box?
为什么带C-4炸弹
Why the C-4?
还有你们究竟要怎么处置我们
And what are you really gonna do with us?
我喜欢你
Oh, I like you.
所以我会最后杀你
That's why I'm gonna kill you last.
捕手约翰
Trapper John.
可以了
We're good to go.
好了
All right.
各位  请移步
Everybody, on your feet.
跟着走  起来起来
Let's go. Up, up, up, up.
你要做什么
What are you gonna do?
你很聪明  我确定你一定能想明白
You're clever. I'm sure you'll figure it out.
还有18分钟  我要大家各就各位
We still got 18 minutes. I want everybody in position.
特警队可以在49街和巴士汇合
S.W.A.T. can rendezvous with the bus here on 49th.
他们可以在那里上车
They can load there.
我希望在这里  这里还有这里安排狙击手
I want snipers here, here, and here.
接通罗曼的电话
Get Roman on the horn.
他为什么没有提要求
Why he didn't ask for something?
什么
What?
长官
Sir...
他给了我20分钟
He gave me 20 minutes,
却没有提要求做交换
and he didn't ask for anything in return.
如果他想要持有掌控权
If he wanted to maintain control,
他一定会提要求的
he would've asked for something.
我是觉得  这样也太容易了
I mean, this is all way to easy.
赢了就接受  警探
Take the win, detective.
不  长官  有些不对劲
No, sir. Something is going on.
我们没问到关键问题  我是说
We are just not asking right questions. I mean,
抢银行为什么要带C-4炸弹
why would he bring C-4 to a bank robbery?
安格斯·菲尔斯的死与抢劫案有什么关系
What does Agnes Fields' murder have to do with any of this?
队长  我和罗曼中士联系上了
Captain, I get Sergent Roman.
你好  罗曼
Yeah, Roman.
妈妈  我觉得自己对这家机构的
Mother, I find I'm no longer satisfied
客户服务不再感到满意了
with the customer service at this establishment.
我想我们得重新选择一家银行
I think we should take our business elsewhere.
-我很抱歉  -这不是你的错
- I'm so sorry. - No.
原谅我把你拖来这里  我
Forgive me for dragging you into this. I--
没事  没事
It's okay. It's okay.
好的
Okay.
我爱你  妈妈
I love you, mother.
我也爱你  孩子
Right back at you, kiddo.
你查到安格斯的什么线索没
Did you find anything on Agnes?
我们查过她的电话记录和财产状况
We've gone over phone and financials
和她朋友邻居也聊过
and talked to friends and neighbours.
没发现什么重要信息
Nothing sticks out.
安格斯的保管箱呢
What about Agnes's safety deposit box?
数月之前就有人假装是她的亡夫
Somebody was pretending to be her dead husband
每月去查看
and accesses since monthly.
有任何线索吗
Any leads?
目前还没发现
Nothing so far.
亲人方面呢
Relatives?
安格斯没什么亲人在世了
Uh, Agnes really didn't have any relatives left.
他丈夫去世了  女儿和孙子
Her husband's dead, her daughter and grandson
一年前在一次沉船事故中丧生
died in a boating accident over a year ago.
她唯一还在世的亲人就是前女婿
Her only surviving relative is a former son-in-law--
朗·布拉德
Ron Brandt.
我们给他留了言  但还没接到回话
We left him a message, we never heard him back yet.
听着  现在我们没时间等他回话
Look, we don't have time to wait for a return phone calls,
所以你们去找...
so find...
卡塞尔
Castle!
他们在这
They're here!
我告诉过你们她会救出我们的
I told you.
我的上帝啊
Oh, my god.
我要开锁了  准备好了吗
Here we go, ready?
好了
OK.
你还好吗
How are you?
你知道吗  他不是唯一被锁的
He's not the only one here, you know?
我真是
Oh, I'm so...
玛莎  真是抱歉
I'm so sorry, Martha.
抱歉  你感觉怎么样
Excuse me. How you doing?
我耳朵有点
My ears are...
每个人质都在吗
Everybody account for?
我们都在这  我们都很好
We're all here. We're all okay.
那些劫匪怎么了
So what happended to the robbers?
他们都死了
They are dead.
被炸飞了
They blew themselves up.
什么
What?
显然  C-4炸药是他们逃走计划的一部分
Apparently, the C-4 was part of the exit strategy.
他们直接从墙底炸开个洞
They blasted a hole straight through the bottom of wall.
炸开通往废弃地铁站的入口
And opened a ceiling on the abandoned subway station below.
如果他们没搞砸的话  真是个完美的计划
Smart plan if they didn't screw it up.
他们肯定是没还隐蔽好就引爆了
They must have triggered the explosion before they took cover,
结果把自己给炸死了
and then they killed themselves.
那不可能
That's not possible.
C-4炸药十分稳定
C-4, it's a very stable exclusive.
它不会意外爆炸的
It wouldn't go off accidentally.
这群家伙可不是便利店强盗
These guys were not dime-store bandits.
他们训练有素  像军人一样
They were trained, they were military precision.
他们不会贸然引爆的
They won't set off a explosion prematurely.
你确定
Really?
我找到的躯体残片告诉我他们的确失手了
I got an assortment of body parts that tells me they did.
我们先出去吧
Let's get outta here.
所有人都平安无事吗
Is everybody okay?
是的  大家都很好
Yeah, they're fine.
他们需要缓缓神
They just need a minute.
我们听说所有疑犯都死了
We heard all the suspects are dead.
这说不通
Guys, none of this makes any sense.
一位老妇人因自己的保管箱钥匙被杀
An old lady is killed for her safe deposit box key,
而她的亡夫每个月都来查看这个保管箱
which her dead husband accesses every month?
然后发生了这起银行劫案
And then this?
我们肯定漏掉了什么线索
There's something that we're missing.
你说的安格斯·菲尔斯唯一在世的亲人呢
What were you saying about Agnes Fields's last surviving relative?
她的前女婿  朗·布拉德
Her former son-in-law-- Ron Brandt.
我们给他留言了  但他在海外有很多业务
We left a message, but he does a lot of bussiness overseas,
也许他根本不在国内
so he may not even be in the country.
他登记的住址是上东区的一栋顶层公寓
He's listed at a penthouse on the upper east side.
我们可以去看看
So we can go check--
等等  这是她女婿
Wait, that's-- that the son-in-law.
是的 怎么了
Yeah, why?
他是其中一名人质
He is one of the hostages.
他刚刚癫痫突然发作
He was having a seizure and...
上帝啊
Oh, God.
我是纽约警局的探长凯特·贝克特
This is Detective Kate Beckett, NYPD.
我想查一名刚因一起银行抢劫案被送进来的病人
I'm checking in on a patient that came in from a bank robbery.
他叫萨尔·马丁诺
His name is Sal Martino.
什么
What?
他出院了
He did?
他不顾医嘱强行出院了
He checked himself out against medical advice.
他跑了
He's gone.
是他  是他自编自演了这一出戏
It was him. He orchestrated this whole thing.
刚查到  朗·布拉德经营一家公司
It turns out, Ron Brandt runs a company
代理军事承包商
that supplies military contractors
其特别作战部队遍布全球
with special operational forces from around the world.
他利用自己的军事关系雇佣了
Ok, he uses his military connection to hire
银行里那些雇佣军
that team of mercenaries in the bank,
为了灭口  他将C4炸弹提前引爆
and then to avoid loose ends, Ron rigs the c-4 to blow early.
这家伙真是冷血
Talk about cold blooded.
他费尽心思只是为了
And he did all of this just for the contents
拿到安格斯的保管箱里的东西吗
of Agnes' safety deposit box?
卡塞尔  你说你看到那里面有些照片和信对吗
Castle, you said that there were photos and letters in that, right?
是的  捕手约翰肯定是在他
Yeah, Trapper John must have given them to Ron
被送去上洗手间的时候将东西给了他
when he was being escorted back from the restroom.
因为那之后  他假装癫痫发作  被送了出去
because right after that, he faked a seizure and was let go.
但为什么呢  到底他前岳母的
But why? I mean, what was so special
保管箱有什么重要的东西值得他这样冒险
about his former mother-in-law's safety deposit box.
前岳母
Former mother-in-law?
对  朗曾经与安格斯的女儿塔尼娅结过婚
Yeah. Ron was married to Agnes' daughter Tanya.
她和她儿子康纳均
Both her and her son Connor were killed
在一年前的一次沉船事故中丧生
in a boating accident about a year ago.
不不  朗跟我提过康纳
No, no, Ron spoke about Connor,
他说话的样子  儿子不像是死掉了
and he did not speak about like he was dead.
康纳还活着
Connor is still alive.
我也没法解释  卡塞尔
Well, I don't know what to tell you, Castle.
这里写的很清楚  康纳死了
It says right here, Connor dead.
这我倒不太确信
I'm not so sure about that.
他的妻子塔尼娅和儿子康纳的尸体
It turns out neither his wife Tanya nor Connor's body
都没有找到
was ever recovered.
他妻子为什么要假死
Why would the wife fake their deaths?
家庭暴力
Domestic abuse.
可是朗利用自己的关系
However, Ron had the connections
与金钱让自己免遭起诉
and the wealth to avoid prosecution.
法律没能保护她
So the system failed her.
她和康纳无法逃脱朗的打骂
She and Connor couldn't escape Ron's abuse,
所以她伪造自己和儿子的死亡然后消失了
so she faked their deaths and disappeared.
但为了彻底消失
Yeah, but to disappear,
她就得抛弃以前的生活
she had to walk away from her former life...
与她认识的所有人和事断绝关系
Sever ties with everything and everyone she ever knew...
但是她放不下她的妈妈安格斯
Except she couldn't, especially with her mother Agnes.
那就是他要保管箱的原因
Which is what the safety deposit box was for.
里面有她们联络的证据
It means the communication.
就像约翰·勒卡雷小说中的冷战投递箱
It's like a cold war drop box in some John Le Carre novel,
但是塔尼娅不会冒险去送信
only Tanya wouldn't be able to risk making the drops.
那是谁替她送信呢
So who would make the drops for her?
那个假扮安格斯亡夫的神秘男子
Our mystery man who was posing as Agnes' dead husband.
他是塔尼娅的中间人
He was Tanya's middleman.
塔尼娅把照片和信给了中间人
Okay, so Tanya sends the photos and the letters to the middleman,
中间人把它们放在保管箱里给安格斯
then the middleman puts them in the safety deposit box for Agnes.
保管箱就像信箱
The box serves as a mailbox.
不过这个比信箱更安全
Only it's better than a mailbox
因为它锁在银行
cause it's locked up in bank.
朗一定是对他们的诈死起了疑心
Ron must have suspected that they fade their deaths
于是开始监听安格斯家
and that's when he bugged Agnes' home.
当朗发现了保管箱的事
When Ron found out about the box,
他为了拿到钥匙杀了安格斯
he killed Agnes for the key.
没错  因为时间紧迫
Right, and with the clock ticking,
他就雇了那个队伍上演银行劫案
he hired that crew to stage the bank robbery
是为拿到钥匙所对应的保管箱
to get to the box with that key.
要知道  那些照片和信件会告诉他
You know, those photos and letters will say
他妻子和儿子到底藏在哪里
exactly where his wife and son are hidng.
他现在正赶往那里
He's on his way there now,
我们都知道他到了之后会做些什么
and we know what he's gonna do once he gets there.
他要绑架他儿子杀了他妻子
He's gonna kidnap his son and kill his wife.
找到中间人
Identifying the middleman
是我们找到塔尼娅和康纳的唯一办法
is the only way we're gonna be able to find Tanya and Connor,
我们都知道什么
so what do we know?
他能伪装成安格斯的亡夫
He passed for Agnes' late husband.
那他一定是个不会引起朗怀疑的人
And it'd have to be someone that Ron wouldn't suspect.
那就排除了朋友  邻居和同事
That rules out friends, neighbors and coworkers.
一定是他们非常信任的人
It must be the private person that they trusted.
但是那人也许是收费的
But the man could been paid.
也许我们可以查查他们的付款记录
Maybe we could track their payments.
也许他们很聪明  都是用现金支付
You know, they're probably smart enough to pay in cash.
那样就无从查证
Which is untraceable.
除非  用支票支付
Unless, if paying by check
不会引发危险
wouldn't have thrown up any red flags.
康纳和塔尼娅假死的时候
At the time of Connor and Tanya's supposed death,
她每月付给圣阿比盖尔教堂一张什一税支票
she was making monthly tithe checks to St. Abigail's church.
谁能比牧师更符合这些特征呢
And who better fits this profile than a priest?
我知道我们该先找谁谈谈
And I know which one we should speak to first.
主持他们葬礼的那个牧师
The priest who officiated their funeral...
肖恩·麦卡斯基神父
Father Sean McCaskey.
麦卡斯基神父  我是凯特·贝克特探长
Father McCaskey, I'm detective Kate Beckett.
这位是理查德·卡塞尔
This is Richard Castle.
我们需要知道塔尼娅和康纳·布拉德的藏身之处
We need to know where Tanya and Connor Brandt are hiding.
我不知道你们在说什么
I don't know what you're talking about.
塔尼娅和康纳已经死了一年多了
Tanya and Connor have been dead for over a year.
神父  你不了解情况
Father, you don't understand.
安格斯·菲尔斯被杀了
Agnes Fields has been murdered.
朗·布拉德拿到了她银行保管箱里的东西
Ron Brandt has the contents of her safe deposit box.
他现在正去找他们
He's on his way to them now.
什么
What?
怎么会这样
How could this happen?
那个盒子放在那里是为了保护他们
That box was there to protect them.
它没能做到  神父  但我们能
It didn't, Father, but we can.
我们需要他们的地址
We need to know their address.
当然可以
Of course.
伊萨卡  卡斯卡迪拉街14号
14 Cascadilla Street, Ithaca.
伊萨卡  只有4小时路程
Ithaca? That's only four hours away.
朗现在可能已经到了
Ron could already be there right now.
-谢谢  -不客气
- Thanks. - Yes.
亲爱的
Honey.
我回来了
I'm home.
退回去
Stay back.
我会杀了你的
I will kill you.
塔尼娅  这就是你欢迎老公的方式吗
Now, Tanya, is this any way to greet your husband?
哦不  亲爱的  你撞到头了
Oh, no, honey. You bumped your head.
我的乖儿子
There's my boy.
想爸爸了没
Did you miss your daddy?
快点啊  快点啊
Come on. Come on.
怎么花了这么长时间
Man, what the hell is taking so long?
居然还让我们等候接听
I can't believe they still got us on hold.
贝克特  如果他抓到了那孩子
Beckett, if he gets ahold of that kid...
不要  妈妈
No! Mommy!
不不不  不要
No, no, no, no.
求你不要带走他  求你
Please don't take him! Please.
别当着他杀我  求你了
Aah! Not in front of him, please!
宝贝
Baby.
我干嘛要杀你呢
Why would I kill you?
我要你长命百岁
I want you to live and long, long life
知道自己再也见不到康纳了
with the knowledge that you're never gonna see Connor again.
现在轮到我玩消失了
Now it's my turn to disappear.
与你不同的是  我会藏
But unlike you, I know how to hide.
-不  -走吧  康纳  走吧
- No! - Come on, Connor. Come on. Come on.
康纳  康纳
Connor! Connor!
我们走  我们走吧
I got you. I got you. I got you.
警察  别动
Police! Don't move!
呆着别动
Right there.
想清楚你该怎么做
Think real hard about your next move.
什么
What?
好  谢谢
Okay. Thanks.
-找到他们了  -太好了
- They found them. - Yes.
塔尼娅得缝几针  但康纳没事
Tanya's gonna need a few stitches, but Connor's okay.
走吧  我们去接他们
Come on. Let's go pick 'em up.
去伊萨卡吗
Ithaca?
就算做个人质
Even as a hostage,
我也能祝你破案
I help you solve murders.
贝克特  我觉得
Beckett, I think...
我觉得你有个最佳搭档
I think you have the perfect partner.
是啊  不过他不喜欢做文书工作
Yeah, except he doesn't like doing paperwork.
说得对
Touche.
老地方
So... old haunt?
我请客
I'll buy you a drink.
不
No.
我有更好的地方
But I'll do you one better.
凯特
Oh, Kate!
亲爱的  你能来太好了
Oh, darling, you can join us.
真棒啊  美女
Oh, you great, beautiful creature,
快进来
come in.
玛莎
Oh, wow, Martha.
你...
You...
真是...
you really...
-实现自我突破了  -没错
- outdid yourself. - I did.
经历了死亡的威胁该庆祝生命的可贵
Facing death demands celebrating life.
今夜我们好好吃一顿
Tonight we feast.
阿丽克西斯呢
Where's Alexis?
她在...
Oh, she's, uh...
-失陪一下  -好
- Excuse me one minute. - Yeah.
-喝吗  -请吧
- So yes? - Please.
阿什  不只是今天的事
Ash, it's not about today.
过去的三个月都是如此
It's about the last 100 days.
我需要的时候你从来不在
You're never here for me.
虽然你在加州
Just because you're in California
不代表我就得屏息凝神
doesn't mean I should have to hold my breath,
交叉双指  对星星许愿
cross my fingers, and wish upon a star
你能回我个短信
just to get a text from you.
都是借口
Yeah, more excuses.
阿什  我不能这么下去了
Ash, I just can't do this anymore.
我们分手吧
We're done.
你还好吗
You okay?
不好
No.
明天再问我一次吧
But ask me again tomorrow.
阿丽克西斯  亲爱的
Alexis, darling,
帮我搞定柳橙鸭肉  拜托了
help me with the duck l'orange, s'il vous plait.
谢谢
Ah, thank you.
我还没来得及好好谢你
And I didn't get a chance to properly thank you
救我一命
for saving my life.
没事的  卡塞尔
Oh, there's no need, Castle.
我们是搭档  应该的
We're partners. It's what we do.
是啊
Yes.
当然了  我们有的人付出更多
Some of us more than others, of course.
等等  这话什么意思
Wait. What is that supposed to mean?
就是说这是你第八次救我
Only that this is the eighth time you've saved my life,
而我救过你九次了
and I've saved your life nine times.
好吧  首先
Okay, first of all,
我真不敢相信你居然还计分
I can't even believe that you're keeping score.
其次  不可能你救我的次数
And secondly, there is no way that you've saved my life
多于我救你
more than I have yours.
九次  拜托
Nine? Please.
那我们来回想一下吧
Well, let's review, shall we?
第一次  我用香槟酒瓶
The first time, I distracted that mad gunman
引开疯狂枪手的注意
with the Champagne bottle.
没错  那算救你  你承认了
And, yes, that was a save. Even you admitted it.
第二次  连环杀手
Second time, the, um, serial killer
趁你洗澡的时候在你厨房里放了个炸弹
who put a bomb in your kitchen while you were taking a shower.
-我穿越地狱般的烈火...  -坐下  坐下
- I had to brave hellish flames... - Sit, sit.
救你于澡盆之中
to pull you out of your bathtub.
这我一时半会可忘不了
I won't be forgetting that anytime soon.